<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>QoS on libert.xyz</title>
    <link>https://libert.xyz/series/qos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in QoS on libert.xyz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 16:06:55 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://libert.xyz/series/qos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Namespaces resources quotas</title>
      <link>https://libert.xyz/posts/namespaces-quotas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 16:06:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libert.xyz/posts/namespaces-quotas/</guid>
      <description>The Limits and Requests are set for each container, what about if we want to apply Limits to namespaces?
LimitRange Object The LimitRange resource. It allows you to specify (for each namespace) not only the minimum and maximum limit you can set on a container for each resource but also the default requests for containers that don’t specify requests.
LimitRange use case A great use case for LimitRange is to prevent users from creating pods that are bigger than the node&amp;rsquo;s resources in the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PODS QoS</title>
      <link>https://libert.xyz/posts/pods-qos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 18:47:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libert.xyz/posts/pods-qos/</guid>
      <description>There is no option or field to assign Quality of service to a pod but a combination between Requests and Limits give us the ability to define Quality of service.
QoS Classes  BestEffort class (no request and limits set) Guaranteed class (requests are equal to limits) Burstable class (one container has limit set but another don&amp;rsquo;t)  Looking at QoS at the POD level is confusing because a POD can have one or multiple containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PODS Requests &amp; Limits</title>
      <link>https://libert.xyz/posts/pods-requests-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 13:15:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libert.xyz/posts/pods-requests-limits/</guid>
      <description>When creating a pod we can specify the amount of CPU and memory that a container needs. If a POD has more than one container requests and limits are specified individually for each container.
E.g.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t specify a CPU request the Kubernetes Scheduler will take the decisions of resource allocations for you. In the worst-case scenario, the container may not get any CPU at all.
Understanding CPU Units The CPU resource is measured in CPU units.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>